<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<LanguageData>
    
    <PlantPotato.label>Potetplante</PlantPotato.label>
    <PlantPotato.description>En simpel plante, med høy næringsværdi. Gror godt, selv i dårlig jord.</PlantPotato.description>
    
    <PlantCorn.label>corn plant</PlantCorn.label>
    <PlantCorn.description>A large grain plant which produces ears of delicious yellow seeds. Takes a relatively long time to grow, but yields lots of food, takes a long time to spoil, and can be happily eaten raw. Needs fertile soil to grow well.</PlantCorn.description>
    
    <PlantRice.label>rice plant</PlantRice.label>
    <PlantRice.description>A low grain plant that thrives in rich soil and yields food fast, but is not nice to eat uncooked.</PlantRice.description>
    
    <PlantHaygrass.label>haygrass</PlantHaygrass.label>
    <PlantHaygrass.description>A mixture of nutrient-rich grasses which yield large amounts of hay. Hay is edible for animals, but not humans.</PlantHaygrass.description>
    
    <PlantStrawberry.label>jordbærplante</PlantStrawberry.label>
    <PlantStrawberry.description>En skrøpelig men legger frukt. Lekker selv når den er rå.</PlantStrawberry.description>
    
    <PlantCotton.label>bomullsplante</PlantCotton.label>
    <PlantCotton.description>Gir bomull, en fin plantefiber som bruges til å lage stoff.</PlantCotton.description>
    
    <PlantDevilstrand.label>djevelstrå</PlantDevilstrand.label>
    <PlantDevilstrand.description>Denne sårbare soppen er genetisk utformet til å produsere silke av den høyeste kvalitet. Ryktes å ha mystiske egenskaper. Den skylder sitt navn til grådigheten som planten inspirerer i folk som produserer den.</PlantDevilstrand.description>
    
    <PlantHealroot.label>healroot</PlantHealroot.label>
    <PlantHealroot.description>A slow-growing plant which yields herbal medicine when harvested.\n\nHealroot was selectively bred for centuries by settlers. It is sometimes also called "healer's hand" by tribespeople - a nickname it owes to its five major medicinal virtues.</PlantHealroot.description>
    
    <PlantHops.label>hop plant</PlantHops.label>
    <PlantHops.description>A flowering plant that yields hops, and essential ingredient in beer.</PlantHops.description>
    
    <PlantRose.label>rose</PlantRose.label>
    <PlantRose.description>En skjønn kultivert blomst.</PlantRose.description>
    
    <PlantDaylily.label>daglilje</PlantDaylily.label>
    <PlantDaylily.description>En søt kultivert blomst.</PlantDaylily.description>
    
</LanguageData>
