<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<LanguageData>

	<ClickToJumpToProblem>Klikk for å hoppe til problemet</ClickToJumpToProblem>




  <AlertNeedStockpile>Trenger lagrings plass</AlertNeedStockpile>
  <AlertNeedStockpileDesc>Kolonistene dine trenger en plass for å lagre ting. Angi et LAGER for dem til å lagre ting i.\n\nFinn lager i sone delen av arkitekt menyen nederst til venstre.</AlertNeedStockpileDesc>

  <AlertUnforbidStartingResources>Uforby resusser</AlertUnforbidStartingResources>
  <AlertUnforbidStartingResourcesDesc>Start resurssene på kartet er forbydd. \n\nFor at kolonistene skal ta dem, må du uforby dem ved å velge dem og trykke på uforby kommandoen nederst på skjermen.</AlertUnforbidStartingResourcesDesc>

  <AlertEquipStartingWeapons>Bruk våpen</AlertEquipStartingWeapons>
  <AlertEquipStartingWeaponsDesc>Kolonistene dine kom med noen våpen. Bruk dem!\n\nVelg hver kolonist og høyre-klikk på våpenet du vil at de skal bruke.</AlertEquipStartingWeaponsDesc>

  <NeedSawmill>Trenger sagbruk</NeedSawmill>
  <NeedSawmillDesc>Du trenger en form for sagbruk å hogge stokker til mer allsidige planker.\n\nBygg et hånd sagbruk eller et elektrisk sagbruk.</NeedSawmillDesc>

  <EquipStartingEquipment>Ta utstyret ditt</EquipStartingEquipment>
  <EquipStartingEquipmentDesc>Du landet med noen våpen. Ta dem fra landings område ditt.\n\nFor å bruke noe, velg en kolonist og høyre klikk på tingen du vil bruke.</EquipStartingEquipmentDesc>

  <MentalBreakSoon>Mentalt gal snart</MentalBreakSoon>
  <MentalBreakSoonDesc>Disse kolonistene nærmer seg det punket der de går gal:\n\n{0}\nForbedre disse kolonistenes psykologi snart eller vil dårlige ting skje.</MentalBreakSoonDesc>

  <MentalBreakImminent>Mentalt gal straks</MentalBreakImminent>
  <MentalBreakImminentDesc>Disse kolonister er kritisk stresset og kan bli gal når som helst:\n\n{0}</MentalBreakImminentDesc>

  <ColonistNeedsRescue>Kolonist trenger hjelp</ColonistNeedsRescue>
  <ColonistsNeedRescue>Kolonister trenger hjelp</ColonistsNeedRescue>
  <ColonistsNeedRescueDesc>Disse kolonistene ligger skadet på bakken:\n\n{0}\nSend en annen kolonist å redde dem og bære dem tilbake til sengen.\n\n(For å redde, velg en annen kolonist og høyre klikk på offret og velg Redd.)</ColonistsNeedRescueDesc>

  <BuildARoom>Bygg et rom</BuildARoom>
  <BuildARoomDesc>Et rom består av separate veggstykker med en dør.\n\nBruk arkitekt menyen nederst til venstre av skjermen for å designere hvor du vil ha ting bygget. Når du designerer noe som skal bli bygget, vil kolonistene dine gjøre arbeidet de kan.</BuildARoomDesc>

  <NeedGrowingZone>Trenger plante område</NeedGrowingZone>
  <NeedGrowingZoneDesc>Du har ingen plante områder.\n\nPlasser et plante område på fruktbar jord gjennom arkitekt menyen.</NeedGrowingZoneDesc>

  <NeedDefenses>Trenger forsvar</NeedDefenses>
  <NeedDefensesDesc>Du har vært her en stund og du har helt sikkert blitt sett. Pirat angrep vil starte snart.\n\nDu burde forberede forsvar.\n\n Bygg noen kanoner.</NeedDefensesDesc>

  <NeedDoctor>Trenger en doktor</NeedDoctor>
  <NeedDoctorDesc>Disse kolonistene trenger medisinsk hjelp, men du har ingen friske kolonister valgt som doktorer.\n\n{0}\nVelg en frisk kolonist til doktor arbeidstypen. Hvis de ikke får medisinsk hjelp, kan sårene aldri bli friskere og kan bli permamente.</NeedDoctorDesc>

  <NeedMiner>Need miner</NeedMiner>
  <NeedMinerDesc>You have designated some rocks to be mined, but no colonist has the Mining work type.\n\nAssign a colonist the Mining work type.</NeedMinerDesc>

  <NeedWarden>Need warden</NeedWarden>
  <NeedWardenDesc>You have a prisoner, but no colonist has the Warden work type.\n\nAssign a colonist the Warden work type.</NeedWardenDesc>

  <LowFood>Low food</LowFood>
  <LowFoodDesc>You only have {0} nutrition worth of food in storage. This is dangerously low.\n\nGrow, buy, find, or kill some food.</LowFoodDesc>

  <NeedColonistBeds>Need colonist beds</NeedColonistBeds>
  <NeedColonistBedsDesc>You have more colonists than you have colonist beds. Someone will lack a place to sleep.\n\nEither make more beds, or change a prisoner bed to a colonist bed.\n\nIf you have no resources, sleeping spots are free and can be placed instantly.</NeedColonistBedsDesc>

  <Starvation>Starvation</Starvation>
  <StarvationDesc>These colonists are starving:\n\n{0}\nGet them some food. You'll need a food source like a nutrient paste dispenser and some food to feed it. Also, make sure they're not drafted.</StarvationDesc>

  <Exhaustion>Exhaustion</Exhaustion>
  <ExhaustionDesc>These colonists are exhausted and need rest:\n\n{0}\nGet them some rest. They'll need a bed marked for colonist use. Also, make sure they're not drafted.</ExhaustionDesc>

  <NeedFoodHopper>Need food hopper</NeedFoodHopper>
  <NeedFoodHopperDesc>You have a nutrient dispenser with no hopper next to it.\n\nTo work, paste dispensers must draw from an adjacent hopper filled with raw food.\n\nBuild a hopper adjacent to the dispenser.</NeedFoodHopperDesc>

  <BuildingNeedsPower>Building needs power</BuildingNeedsPower>
  <BuildingsNeedPower>Buildings need power</BuildingsNeedPower>
  <BuildingsNeedPowerDesc>These power-using buildings are totally disconnected from all possible power sources:\n\n{0}\nConnect them to a power generator or battery.</BuildingsNeedPowerDesc>
  <AndMore>and more</AndMore>

  <NeedMealSource>Need meal source</NeedMealSource>
  <NeedMealSourceDesc>You have no way of preparing proper meals from raw food.\n\nBuild a nutrient paste dispenser or a cook stove.\n\n(It cannot be in a prison cell, otherwise colonists cannot use it.)</NeedMealSourceDesc>

  <NeedHomeRegion>Need home region</NeedHomeRegion>
  <NeedHomeRegionDesc>You need to define a HOME REGION where your colonists will clean, extinguish fires, and repair things.\n\nDefine a home region using the ZONES section of the ARCHITECT menu.</NeedHomeRegionDesc>

  <NeedBatteries>Need batteries</NeedBatteries>
  <NeedBatteriesDesc>You only have solar generators and no batteries. This means you'll lose power every time the sun goes down.\n\nBuild a battery or two to get you through the night.</NeedBatteriesDesc>

  <NoTradingCapacity>No trading capacity</NoTradingCapacity>
  <NoTradingCapacityDesc>You have no way of trading with passing ships.\n\nBuild a comms console.</NoTradingCapacityDesc>

  <NeedResearchProject>Need research project</NeedResearchProject>
  <NeedResearchProjectDesc>You have the equipment to do research but have not selected a project.\n\nOpen the research menu and select a project.</NeedResearchProjectDesc>

  <NeedDump>Need dump</NeedDump>
  <NeedDumpDesc>You have marked {0} to be hauled, but the colonists have nowhere to take it.\n\nDesignate a stockpile and set its storage settings to accept {0}.</NeedDumpDesc>

  <NeedGrave>Need grave</NeedGrave>
  <NeedGraveDesc>There is a dead body laying on the ground and nowhere for your colonists to take it.\n\nBuild a grave or a dumping zone and set their storage settings.</NeedGraveDesc>

  <ColonistsIdle>{0} colonists idle</ColonistsIdle>
  <ColonistsIdleDesc>These colonists are wandering idly:\n\n{0}\nYou should probably find them something productive to do.</ColonistsIdleDesc>

  <HaltedConstructions>{0} constructions are missing materials</HaltedConstructions>
  <HaltedConstructionsDesc>These constructions are missing materials:\n\n{0}\nYou should probably make required materials available for your colonists.</HaltedConstructionsDesc>

  <TableNeedsChairs>Table needs chairs</TableNeedsChairs>
  <TableNeedsChairsDesc>You have a table with no chairs next to it. Tables are useless unless people can sit at them.</TableNeedsChairsDesc>

  <ColonistNeedsTreatment>Colonist needs treatment</ColonistNeedsTreatment>
  <ColonistNeedsTreatmentDesc>These colonists need medical treatment. Without it, they may die of their wounds, or their wounds may become permanent.\n\n{0}\nTreat them by sending them to a medical bed.\n\n(First, assign a medical bed by selecting it and toggling it into a medical bed. Then, select the wounded colonists and right-click on the medical bed to make them a patient.)</ColonistNeedsTreatmentDesc>


</LanguageData>